Register of the Julius Epstein Papers, 1939-1975
Hoover Institution Archives
- CORRESPONDENCE. (Boxes 107-113.)
  - Miljukow article (sent to...)
  - Miller, Mary
  - Milwaukee Deutsche Zeitung
  - Mittag (Dusseldorf)
  - Mittler, E. S. & Son Verlag
  - Molotov, Viacheslav
  - Monod, N.
  - Moora, Robert L. (New York Herald Tribune, Washington office)
  - Moore, Herbert
  - Moral Re-Armament (Frank Buchman)
  - Morawski, Ignace (Novy Swiat)
  - Morgan, Josa
  - Moss, John E.
  - National Catholic Welfare Conference
  - National Committee For A Free Europe
  - Neue Volkszeitung
  - New York Herald Tribune
  - Overseas Press Club of America
  - Possony, Stefan (documents from the "Auswartiges Amt," Germany, 1915-1916, and from the "Ministerium des Aussern, Austria, 1917)
  - Spiro, Lilli
  - Spittler, Felix A., M.D.
  - St. Moritz hotel (New York)
  - Stadlmayer, V., Dr., Mrs.
  - Stepankovsky, W. J.
  - Stern (Hamburg)
  - Stern Brothers
  - Stevens & Sons, Ltd. (London)
  - Stocker, Helene
  - Storm Publishers
  - Stout, Frank
  - Straka, J. A.
  - Strobel, Georg W.
  - Thorwald, Jurgen
  - "Warner" documents, 2 folders)
- SUBJECT FILE. (Boxes 114-166.)
  - Abel, Rudolph I, Colonel (Box 114)
  - Abernathy, Ralph, Reverend
  - Acheson, Dean
    - "Ethics in Foreign Relations"
    - Obituary
  - Action therapy
  - Adenauer, Konrad (obituaries)
  - Adorno, Theodor W. (obituary)
  - Africa
    - General
    - Economic conditions
    - Economy (New York Times)
  - Aggressive war (Box 115)
  - Agnew, Spiro T.
    - Katyn stamp
    - Speech against TV network
  - Alaska
  - Albania
  - Alexander, Harold, Sir (obituray)
  - Alexander I of Russia (Manifest of 1806)
  - "All the News That's Fit to Print"
  - Allen, Richard V.
  - Allen-Scott Report (7 folders) and J. E.'s dossier
  - Allied code broken by Nazis
  - Alliluyeva, Svetlana, 2 folders)
  - Alsop, Joseph
  - Amateurs (efforts benefit science)
  - "America's Concentration Camps"
  - American Council on Germany
  - American POWs in four wars (World War I and II, Korea, Vietnam)
  - American slang expressions
  - American-Soviet summit meeting, Moscow, May 1972. See Soviet-American summit, May 1972
  - American wars
  - Amnesty International
  - 'Anastasia' - Anna Anderson
  - The Anderson Papers
  - Angina pectoris
  - Anguilla (West Indies)
  - Apartheid
  - Apollo X
  - Apollo XI
  - Apollo XI (Box 116)
  - Apollo vs. Scrag
  - Apt, Austin J.
  - Archiv der Gegenwart (archives of the present)
  - "Are the Russians Ten Feet Tall?"
  - Arendt, Hannah
  - Armenian massacre
  - Arnold, Benedict
  - Aron, Raymond (on Vietnam)
  - Article 19 of the United Nations Charter
    - General, 3 folders)
    - Draft test
    - Resolutions
  - Artukovic, Andrija, Dr.
  - Ashbrook, John M.
    - General
    - Vs. Laird
  - Assembly of Captive European Nations
  - Asylum, 2 folders)
  - Attica rebellion
  - Austria
    - General. See Poland
    - Anti-semitism
  - Azar material
  - Baarslag, Karl
  - Bahmer, Robert H., Dr., 2 folders)
  - Baker, Bobby - Case
  - Balabanoff, Angelica (obituary)
  - "Balance Sheet of 50 Years" (New York Times, 1967) (Box 117)
  - Balance sheet of the summit conferences with the Soviet Union
  - Baldwin, Hanson
  - Balfour Declaration
  - Barghoorn, Prof. Frederick
  - Barnett, Frank R.
  - Barth, Karl (obituary)
  - Bauer, Leo (obituary)
  - Beacon Press
  - Benes' widow
  - Berkeley Barb
  - Berkeley revolt
  - Berkeley Tribe
  - Berner Tagwacht
  - Bessarabia
  - Biafra
  - Bibliography on the world communist movement
  - The Bilderbergers' Woodstock Meeting
  - Birch, John
  - Birch Society
  - Birth control decree (Munich)
  - Bleiburg tragedy (Croatians under Tito)
  - Bollman, Werner
  - Bolshevist early declarations
  - Bomb-terror age, U.S.
  - Bonn
    - And East Germany
    - And Red China
  - Bosch resolution
  - Bothmer, Dietrich von
  - Bozell, Brent
  - Bradley, Omar (on Montgomery)
  - Brandt, Karl, 2 folders)
  - Brandt, Peter (Willy Brandt's son)
  - Brandt, Willy
    - General
    - Letter to Kennedy
  - Brauer, Max (obituary)
  - Braun, Werner von, "Sturm zu den Sternen" (storm in the stars)
  - Brezhnev, Leonid (speeches)
    - November 6, 1964, 2 folders)
    - January 16, 1970 (on Soviet economy)
    - May 21, 1973 (on German TV)
  - Brisson, Pierre (obituary)
  - British Cabinet Papers, 1939
  - British Official Secrets Act, 2 folders)
  - Brown, Constantine (obituary)
  - Brownfeld, Allan C. (the Peking connection)
  - Buchheit, Gert
  - Buckley, William F., Jr.
  - Budenz, Louis F. (obituary)
  - Bukovsky, Vladimir
  - Bulgaria
  - Bullitt, William C.
    - Balkans invasion
    - Obituary
  - Bunche, Ralph, Dr. (obituary)
  - Bundy, MacGeorge
  - Byrnes, James (obituary)
  - Calendar, 1753-2000
  - California coast map
  - Calley, William L., Jr.
  - Campbell, W. Glenn, Dr., Memorandum to
  - Canada (Box 118)
  - Canaris, George
  - Capital punishment (U.S.S.R.)
  - Castro, Fidel
    - And Mao
    - Sulzberger interview
  - Castro, Juanita
  - Central American Common Market
  - Central Intelligence Agency, 3 folders)
  - Chamberlain, John
  - Chaplin, Charlie (back in the U.S., 1972)
  - Chemical warfare
  - Chiang Kai-shek
  - China (dope smuggler)
  - Choltitz, General von
  - Chommanard (law examination)
  - Chou En-lai - Interview
  - Christian Anti-Communist Crusade
  - Chukovsky, Kornei I. (obituary)
  - Churchill, Winston
    - "A New Appraisal of Winston Churchill"
    - "Churchill at 90"
    - Interview of 1901 is published in 1966
    - Moran's story (Churchill's private doctor)
    - On the cold 'peace' and our future
    - Obituaries
  - Classification vs. declassification (United States and Great Britain, January 1972)
  - Cleaver, Eldridge
  - Clifford, Clark M. (on U.S. role in Vietnam)
  - Cliveden (Great Britain)
  - Cohn, Roy
  - Cold war history (Andre Fontaine)
  - Colloredo-Mansfield, Count (obituary)
  - Communist tactics, strategy, and objectives
  - Communist treatment of prisoners of war
  - Commonwealth Club
  - Congo
    - Policy of the U.S.
    - Rebel atrocities
    - UN debate, 1964
  - Congressional Record
    - Katyn Forest Massacre
    - Soviet Cosmonauts' death
  - Consular Treaty (Box 119)
  - Copyright reform
  - Cornell, James C., Jr.
  - Coste, Brutus
  - Costello, Frank
  - Council Against Communist Aggression, 4 folders)
  - Court of World Public Opinion
  - Crime, Definition of
  - Crimean Tartars
  - Crocker, George N.
    - General
    - "Roosevelt's Road to Russia"
  - Cuban millionaires in exile
  - Cuban missile crisis
  - Czech writers
  - Dada
  - Daily press, Guide to
  - Daly, John Charles, Jr.
  - Day, Dorothy
  - D.D.R. (Democratic Republic of Germany)
  - Dean, Vera Micheles
  - Declarations of war (World War I)
  - Defense contractors
  - "Defining War Crimes," by Telford Taylor
  - Definition of 'aggression'
  - Defregger, Bishop
  - Delaney, Edward L., 2 folders)
  - Dennen, Leon, "Tzar Nicholas Thrown Out 50 Years Ago Today"
  - Dentists
  - Department of the Army (Office of the Chief of Psychological Warfare)
  - De-Stalinization (including a study by J. E., "Is there a De-Stalinization?")
  - Diggers, The
  - 'Diploma mills'
  - 'Dismembering' of the U.S.S.R.
  - Divorce law, New York
  - Djilas, Milovan (Box 120)
    - General
    - Interview, 1968
  - Dodd, Thomas J.
    - Boyd's story in the Saturday Evening Post
    - Fullbright statements on Vietnam
    - Investigation, 3 folders)
    - Libel suit against Drew Pearson
    - Obituary
  - Dollar inflation (1900-1969)
  - Donitz, Karl (assails Eisenhower)
  - Dozer, Donald M., Professor
  - Drachkovitch, Milorad M.
  - Dresden
  - Dreyfus Papers
  - Dubcek, Alexander
  - Dulles, Eleanor, Dr.
  - Duplicate clippings
  - East India Company
  - East Turkestan
  - East-West trade
  - Eban, Abba (secret speech)
  - Ehrenburg, Ilya
  - Einstein Papers (New York Times) (Box 121)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D.
    - General
    - Vs. Eisenhower
    - Letter to Diem, 1954
    - "The Eisenhower Myth"
    - "Some Questions Ike Never Answered"
    - On unconditional surrender
  - Ellsberg, Daniel
    - Indictment
    - Trial
  - "Enemy and Ally, Russia"
  - Epstein, Julius. See also On J. E. and Own articles
    - Bibliographical data
    - On him
      - General
      - October 1959-1962
      - 1962
      - 1963
      - Clippings (Box 122)
      - Hunter Arrow
      - Jacobsen, Edmund
      - Polish American Journal
      - Reaction to Katyn campaign, 2 folders)
      - Reference folder
  - Etzioni, Amitai (insurance plan as antipoverty measure)
  - Eudin, Xenia Joukoff
  - Euphemism
  - European union, History of
  - Evans, M. Stanton
  - Expellee Press Service
  - Expellees
  - Fabian, Bela
  - Fainsod, Merle
  - Finland
  - Finletter (Thomas Knight)
  - Fischer, Louis (obituary)
  - Fitzpatrick, Linda
  - Flying saucers
    - General, 2 folders)
    - Apollo XII - UFO sights
  - Forced labor camps - U.S.S.R., 1968
  - Forced repatriation of Soviet prisoners of war
    - Documentation
    - Draft resolution, 1971
    - "Guide to the Care..."
    - National Archives documents, 1972
    - Yalta agreement
  - Foreign aid (tables)
  - Fortas, Abe, Justice (Box 123)
  - Foundations
  - Four Power Agreement on West Berlin, 1971
  - Franco, Francisco (and the Kremlin)
  - Franklin, Bruce
  - Franz, Joseph
  - Frawley, Patrick J., Jr.
  - Freeman, Roger A.
  - Freemasonry
  - French Communist Party (vs. Moscow)
  - Freud, Sigmund
    - General, 3 folders)
    - Correspondence with Jung
  - Friedrich, Paul J.
  - Frings, Joseph, Cardinal
  - Fulbright, J. W.
  - Future (population boom)
  - Gandhi, Indira
  - Gandhi, Mahatma
  - Garner, John Nance (obituary)
  - Gaulle, Charles de
    - General
    - Declaration of May 30, 1968
    - And Kosygin declaration
    - And NATO
    - Press conference of November 27, 1967
    - TV address of May 24, 1968
    - Warning on Vietnam to Kennedy
    - Obituaries
  - Genocide
    - Convention
    - In the U.S.S.R.
  - George, Manfred, Dr. (obituaries)
  - German documents (secrets of the Nazi archives)
  - German Government, 1964-
  - German-Polish Treaty, November 20, 1970. See Polish-German Treaty, November 20, 1970
  - German unofficial peace feelers
  - Germans and Jews of the U.S.S.R.
  - Germany
    - General. See Poland
    - In UN debate
  - Gerstenmaier, Eugen (Box 124)
  - Gestapo (arrest list for England)
  - Gibraltar
  - Gilbert, G. M., Dr. (Nuremberg diary)
  - Glaser, Kurt
  - Glasser, William
  - Goddard Space Flight Center
  - Goldberg, Arthur J.
  - Goldwater, Barry
    - Concedes defeat
    - On Eisenhower
  - Goleniewski, Michal
  - Gomulka, Andrei (asked for Soviet troops in December 1970)
  - Goranevskaya, Natalya E.
  - Graham, Billy
  - Grand Old Party (reply to Johnson)
  - Grant, Natalie
  - Great Soviet documents, 2 folders)
  - Grewe, Wilhelm, Professor
  - Griswold, A. Whitney (president of Yale)
  - Gromyko before the UN, 1967
  - Groner Papers, 5 folders)
  - Gross, Ernest A. (South West Africa case) (Box 125)
  - Guarantees
  - Guatemala, 2 folders)
  - Gubser, Charles S., 2 folders)
  - Guerrilla warfare
    - General
    - In the U.S.
  - Guevara, Ernesto Che
    - General
    - Diary
  - H-bomb ('too efficient' for warfare)
  - Haberl, Gerlinde
  - Haffner, Sebastian, 3 folders)
  - Hahn, Otto, Dr. (obituary)
  - Halle, Louis J.
  - Hallucinogen
  - Hammarskjold, Dag
    - Death
    - And Nasser - Agreement
  - Hammond, Thomas J.
  - Hanoi (secret peace proposals, 1972)
  - Harrimann, W. Averell, 2 folders)
  - Harrisse, Henry
  - Hazlitt, Henry
  - Hearst, William Randolph, Jr. (on forced repatriation)
  - Hebrew 2nd Century how-to book
  - Hegel
  - Hellman, Lilian
  - Helsinki Conference, 1969
  - Henningsen, Manfred, Dr.
  - Herzl, Theodor
  - Hess, Karl
  - Hess, Rudolf
    - General
    - Article by J. E.
    - British newspapers
    - Clippings, 2 folders)
    - House of Lords debate
    - San Francisco Examiner
    - State Department, Office of German Affairs
  - Higgins, Marguerite
  - Hijacking record
  - Hildebrand, Dietrich von
  - Hindu-Moslem hatred
  - Hitler, Adolf
    - "Can Now Return"
    - Daughter
    - Death
    - Defended
    - "Is not Dead"
  - Ho Chi Minh (obituaries)
  - Hochhut, Rolf
  - Hoffner, Eric
  - Hofmannsthal, E. von, Dr.
  - Hoggan, Dave L.
    - General
    - Debate
  - Hohenzollern (Kaiser Wilhelm II)
  - Hong Kong railroad
  - Hoover, Herbert (Box 126)
    - 90th birthday
    - Ideas (for the Hoover Institution)
    - Nobel prize?
  - Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace
  - Hoover Institution conferences
    - 1967
    - 1969
  - Hornbeck, Stanley K., "Communism at Work in China"
  - House Resolution 399
  - Howley, General Frank L.
  - Hue massacre
  - Human Rights and Genocide Conventions
  - 'Humane' weapons
  - Hungary
  - "Hunger in der Welt" (hunger in the world)
  - Hunt, H. L.
  - Hurley, Patricia
  - Hussein, King of Jordan
  - Hutschneker, Arnold A., M.D.
  - Immigration law, 2 folders)
  - India
    - General
    - Food problems
    - Moslems
    - 'Untouchables'
  - Indonesia (leaves the UN)
  - Industries (Fortune's list of the 500 top industries, 1972)
  - Inform National Reports
  - Information Act
  - International Platform Association
  - Iran, 2 folders)
  - Israel (declaration of independence)
  - Israeli-Arab war, 1967
  - Israeli gun boat plot
  - Jackson, Robert H. (Katyn statement)
  - Jaksch, Wenzel (obituary)
  - Japan
    - Demands for return of Kuriles
    - Surrender attempts
  - Japanese rocketeers
  - Jenkins case
  - Jesuit Order
  - Jesus' death
  - Jewish organizations
  - Jews of the U.S.S.R. See Germans and Jews of the U.S.S.R.
  - Joesten, Joachim ('Kennedy murder')
  - Johnson, Howard (obituary)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B.
    - "Instant History"
    - Interviews
    - "Johnson vs. Reagan? God Help Us"
    - Speeches
      - Inaugural speech of January 20, 1965
      - March 31, 1968
      - San Antonio speech on Vietnam
    - State of the Union Message, 1968
    - Ramparts
    - "World War III" story
  - Johnsson, Stephen, Dr.
  - Judaism
    - "Das Judentum im bolschewistischen Vorfeld" (Judaism in the Bolshevik foreground)
    - "Judentum und Musik" (Judaism and music)
  - Kapitza, Pyotr L., 3 folders)
  - Katushev, Konstantin F. (Box 127)
  - Katyn Forest Massacre, 1940
    - General, 2 folders)
    - Congressmen visit Poland
    - Congressional Record - Derwinski
    - "An Echo of Katyn" (New York Herald Tribune, March 29, 1953)
    - Material
    - Memorial Monument, 1972
    - Memorial Stamp
    - Papers
  - Katz-Suchy, Julius
  - Keelhaul cartoon
  - Keller, Helen
  - Kemper, Edmund (mass murderer)
  - Kennan, George
    - On Red China and the UN
    - On Vietnam
  - Kennedy, Edward M. (letter to Evelle Younger)
  - Kennedy, John F.
    - Addison's disease
    - Assassination
    - Brain
    - Library
    - Memorial Library
    - Pledge on Cuba
    - Round
  - Kennedy, Robert F.
  - Kennedys ("The Holy Kennedys: How They're Taking Over")
  - Kerensky, Alexander
    - General
    - On Lenin
    - Revolution, 1917-1967
    - Obituary
  - Khrushchev, Nikita S. (Box 128)
    - Interview, 1967
    - Letter to Kennedy
    - Memoirs
    - Ouster, 6 folders)
    - Purge trial
    - Rebuked on farms
    - Obituaries
  - Kiesinger, Kurt George (German Chancellor)
    - As witness
    - Cabinet, December 1, 1966
  - Kimmel, Husband E., Admiral (obituary) (Box 129)
  - King, Martin Luther, Dr.
  - Kirk, Russell (on Tschombe)
  - Kissinger, Henry Alfred
    - General
    - "Peace Is at Hand"
    - Saves Mao
  - Klein, Julius (Dodd case)
  - Knappstein, Heinrich
  - Koch, Ilse
  - Kodak Instamatic 60 (warranty and instructions)
  - Kohn, Hans, Dr. (on nationalism)
  - Koniev, Marshal (obituary)
  - Korea - Vietnam
  - Kostring, Ernst, General
  - Kosygin, Alexei
    - Interviews, 2 folders)
    - J. E.'s letter to
  - Kraslow, David and Loory, Stuart, "Peace Search"
  - Kraus, Karl
    - General
    - Handwritten letter
  - Krause, Arthur J., Dr.
  - Kremlin's secret letter, 1966
  - Krock, Arthur (on the UN)
  - Kurile Islands
  - Kux, Dr.
  - Kuznetsov, Anatoly
  - Lady Bird's brother
  - Lane, Mark
  - Laser computer
  - Law of treaties
  - Law and Order Conference (Oakland, California)
  - Lazardus, Emma
  - Leaders at Yalta
  - Leaks (of U.S. secrets)
  - Leary, Timothy
  - Least developed states
  - 'Left' university
  - Leger, Paul-Emile, Cardinal
  - Lenin
  - Lerner, Max (Box 130)
  - Letters to the editor (J. E.)
    - General, 3 folders)
    - Hess, Rudolf, 3 folders)
    - Hungarian refugees
    - Macao
    - Russell, Bertrand, Lord
    - Soviet space failures
    - Ullrich, Johannes, Dr., 6 folders)
  - Levine, Isaac Don, 2 folders)
  - Liberty Lobby (Drew Pearson)
  - Liberty, 1971
  - Lincoln, Abraham
    - General
    - "Abraham Lincoln and the Rothschilds"
  - Lincoln University
    - Appointment of J. E. to full professorship
    - Course of international law, 1972-1973
    - Exams, grades, etc.
    - Lectures (international law, 1972)
    - Stationery
  - Lindsay, Sir Ronald
  - Lingens, Paul, Dr. (Box 131)
  - Lippmann, Walter, 3 folders)
  - Lipski, Josef
  - Lithuania
  - 'Live or die decision' of British doctors
  - Livingstone, David, Dr.
  - Long, Edward (Pearson column)
  - Lonsdale, Gordon
  - Loory, Stuart. See Kraslow, David
  - Louis, Victor
  - Lowenthal, Richard
  - L.S.D.
  - Lubke, Heinrich, President
  - Lucas, Jim G. (testimony)
  - Luce, Henry R. (obituary)
  - Lutz-Ford civil lawsuit
  - Lysenko, Denisovich
    - General
    - Condemned, 1964
  - Macedonia
  - Mackintosh, Malcolm (interview)
  - Macmillan, Harold
  - Madariaga, Salvador de
  - Mafia
    - "Cosa Nostra"
    - In the U.S.
  - Maisky, Ivan M.
  - Malcolm X
  - Malone, George W. (Far East situation)
  - Manchester, William
    - Look story
    - Stern story, 2 folders)
  - "Manchurian Booty and International Law"
  - Manila Conference, 1963
  - Manly, Chesly (obituary)
  - Mann, Erica (obituary)
  - Mann, Klaus
  - Mann, Thomas (letters)
  - Manuscripts (J. E.)
    - English
    - German
  - Mao Tse-tung
    - General
    - Agents
      - In India
      - In Western Europe
    - Albania
    - Anti-Mao plot
    - 9th Congress of the CPC
    - Drug pusher, 2 folders)
    - Nuclear industry
    - Policy
    - Revolution (death toll)
    - Secret service
    - "Three Essays"
    - United Nations
    - Wife
  - March of Conferences (list of Allied Conferences during World War II)
  - Marcuse, Herbert
  - Masaryk, Jan
    - Life story
    - Murder admitted
    - Saturday Evening Post, "Was Masaryk Murdered?"
  - Masaryk, Thomas G.
  - Masterman, John, Sir, "The Double-Cross System"
  - Maurois, Andre (obituary)
  - McCabe, Charles, 2 folders) (Box 132)
  - McNamara, Robert S.
    - General
    - Address as World Bank's new president
    - Life interview
  - Medicare handbook
  - Medvedev, Jaures
  - Menninger, William C., Dr. (obituary)
  - Mercury menace
  - Michael, Franz (testimony, July 1971)
  - Microstates
  - Mihajlov, Mihajlo
    - General
    - On Djilas
  - Mikolajczyk, Stanislaw (obituary)
  - Mills College
  - "Minimum Treatment of Prisoners"
  - Minolta-16 (photographs)
  - MIRVs
  - Missiles
  - Moczar, General
  - Mongolia (including the Constitution of 1924)
  - 'Monkey Law'
  - Monogamy 'unconstitutional'
  - Montgomery, Viscount of Alamein
    - General
    - Memoirs
  - Moon
    - 1969
    - Medals
    - Memorial, Apollo XV, 1971
  - Moorhead, William S. (Chairman of the Foreign Operations and Government Information Subcommittee - Hearings, June 18, 1971)
  - Morgenthau, Hans J.
  - Mormons
  - Morse, Arthur D., "While 6 Millions Die"
  - Moscow
    - Communist Parties Conference, 1969
    - Hardline in Germany
    - Speaking
  - Moseley, C. C.
  - Mosher trial papers (Julius Epstein vs. Stanley Resor)
  - Mowrer, Edgar Ansel
  - Moynihan, Daniel Patrick
  - Mozart
  - Muggeridge, Malcolm
  - Munich, 1938
  - Murphy, George
  - Musmanno, Michael A., Justice, 2 folders)
  - My Lai (Prosecutor Daniels' letter to Nixon)
  - Myrdal, Gunnar
  - Nader, Ralph (on Freedom of Information Act)
  - Nagy, Imre, 2 folders)
  - NANA (J. E.'s articles)
  - Nansen, Fridjov
  - NASA
    - General
    - Layoffs
  - Nash, Ogden (obituary)
  - Nasser, Gamal Abdel
    - General
    - Crisis
    - Obituaries
  - National Archives Conference, 1971
  - NATO
    - General
    - Communique, December 17, 1964
    - Declaration, December 5, 1969
    - Sulzberger articles
  - Nazis
    - Crime statute expires
    - Press
    - On Roosevelt
  - N.D.P. (National Democratic Party of Germany, neo-nazi)
  - Negro revolt
  - Neruda, Pablo (on Solzhenitsyn)
  - Die neue Gesellschaft
  - Neutrality (Box 133)
  - New German history
  - New math
  - New York Times
    - Biographies
    - Data
    - Editorials
    - Letters to the editor
    - News not fit to print
  - New Zealand dunes
  - News headlines, 1964
  - Newton, Isaac
  - Nicholas II, Tsar (escape route)
  - Nicolaevsky, Boris (obituaries)
  - Nicolson, Harold, Sir (obituary)
  - Nigeria
  - Nisei internment camp
  - Nixon, Richard
    - China trip, 1972, 4 folders)
    - Declassification
      - Program
      - World War II Papers
    - Elected President, 1968
    - Foreign Affairs Message, February 18, 1970
    - J. E.'s letter to
    - Miami, 1968
    - Speech, November 3, 1969
    - Thailand statement
    - "Withholds His Peace Ideas"
  - Nkruma, Kwame
    - General
    - Subversion
  - Nobel Prize
    - 1967 (Winners)
    - Cassin, Rene
    - Literature
      - 1901-1970
      - How the winner is chosen
  - Nolte, Richard H. (statement on U.S.S.R., Nasser and 6-days war)
  - Non-aligned nations
  - Non-governmental organizations at the United Nations
  - Nonproliferation Treaty
  - Nonviolence school (Joan Baez)
  - North Sea (pirate TV)
  - Norton, Carole (on J. E.'s manuscript, "Forced Repatriation")
  - Novotny, Antonin
  - Nuclear bombs in the U.S.
  - Nuclear weapons at Vatican II
  - Oder-Neisse line
  - On Julius Epstein
    - General, 4 folders)
    - American Legion, 1952 (Katyn Forest Massacre)
    - Announcement of his case against the U.S.
    - Arizona Republic
    - Ashbrook, John M. (introducing House Resolution 399)
    - Cartoon
    - The Catholic News (Edith Kermit Roosevelt column) (Box 134)
    - CBS Radio News editorial, July 26, 1971
    - Chicago Tribune, 5 folders)
    - Christian Crusade Weekly, June 20, 1971
    - Clippings
    - Congressional Record
      - Ashbrook, John M., 3 folders)
      - Crane, Phillip M., 2 folders)
      - Epstein vs. Resor, October 14, 1970
    - Connecticut Herald, September 19, 1971
    - Devin-Adair Prospect
    - Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace (Report 1966-1969)
    - Human Events, 4 folders)
    - Los Angeles Times, 3 folders) (Box 135)
    - Manchester Union Leader, March 10, 1971 (Gardiner column)
    - Midnight
    - Moss Act trial
    - National Review, 2 folders)
    - New York Times, 4 folders)
    - News-Leader, November 30, 1972 (Keelhaul)
    - News release, November 29, 1970 (telegram to Nixon)
    - Novoye Russkoye Slovo, 2 folders)
    - Oklahoman, 3 folders)
    - Palo Alto Times, 6 folders)
    - Peninsula Living, January 9, 1971
    - Phyllis Schlafly Report, October 1971
    - Press conferences, 2 folders)
    - Radio Free Europe Broadcast (Sukiennicki)
    - Rarick, John R.
    - Redwood City Tribune, November 9, 1970
    - Saga, March 1968 (Soviet cosmonauts)
    - San Diego Union, September 22, 1968
    - San Francisco Examiner
    - Santa Barbara News-Press, June 7, 1970
    - "The Spiegel Affair"
    - Stanford Daily, 2 folders) (Box 136)
    - Stanford University News Service, 7 folders)
    - Steenberg, Sven, "Vlasov"
    - Time, July 5, 1971
    - Trial
      - District Court, San Francisco
      - Epstein vs. Froehlke
    - Truth Forum, 2 folders)
    - U.P.I. release